Hey guys, welcome back to our IELTS Listening course.
In the previous lesson, we learned the steps
to tackle map labeling question type in the
IELTS Listening course.
Let's do a quick exercise to review those steps.
Did you get all the steps correctly?
Great job.
Here are the steps for map labeling questions
in the IELTS Listening test.
Step one, read the instructions carefully to note
whether you're required to write the locations or
fill in the letter A, B, C, or D.
Step two, read the map.
Step three, identify the starting point and the
order of directions and locations.
Step four, listen and fill in the blanks.
Step five, write the correct answers.
Now, let's practice these steps with an exercise.
Here's today's listening test.
Looking at this question, what should we do first?
Step one, read the instructions carefully to note
whether you're required to write the locations or
fill in the letter A, B, C, or D.
In this exercise, you only need to write
the letters A to I in the blanks.
Step two, read the map.
You should note that you only have a
few seconds to read the map, so quickly
read the given locations, especially pay close attention
to the directions and names of locations needed to be found.
In this map, we need to highlight these locations.
Main entrance, information desk, emergency exit, staff room,
and cafe.
Step three, identify the starting point and the
order of directions and locations.
With our map, it is very likely that
the starting point is at the main entrance,
which is at the bottom of the map.
After entering, you will see the information desk
at the center of the building.
This can be a reference point when the
narrator explains how to get to other locations.
For maps with location names, we should also
highlight the names in the questions.
These are names of locations, so they are
unchangeable keywords and will appear in the audio.
Make sure to spend time reading through all
of them to familiarize yourself with how to
pronounce the names.
Step four, listen and fill in the blanks.
While listening, we should also keep an eye
on the surroundings of the place we're seeking.
If we miss a piece of information, quickly
catch the keyword to move on to the next location.
Step five, write the correct answers.
Finally, don't forget to revisit the instructions to
check whether we need to write the letter
A, B, C, or D, or the full name of the locations.
Now let's listen to the audio
and write down the answers on your paper.
Now listen and answer questions 11 to 17.
Good morning, everyone,
and welcome to the City Technology Institute.
My name is Sarah, and I'll be giving you
a brief orientation of our new Science of the Future wing
before you explore it on your own.
If you look at your maps, we are
currently standing at the main entrance.
Directly in front of you, in the middle
of the hall, is the information desk.
If you lose your group, please meet back here.
First, there is a space in our museum
that is full of science books and kits
that you can take home.
It's the museum shop.
Right immediately as you enter the building through
the main entrance, you will see the shop
on your right.
Directly across from the shop, on the other side of the entrance,
is the Evolution of Computers gallery.
This is a great place to start your visit,
because you can see how computers have
changed from giant machines into the small phones
we use today.
From this room, if you walk a bit further,
you'll come to the room located halfway.
It's our Renewable Energy Exhibit, where there are
interactive screens that show
how much energy the city is using right now.
Now, I know lots of you are interested in the robotics lab.
To head there, let's go along
the right hand wall of the building.
You will find it right opposite the information desk.
And there is a cafe there,
so you can sit and have a drink while you
watch our engineers working on new robot designs
through the large windows.
If you keep walking toward the back of
the building, you will find the room in
the far top right-hand corner.
This is the Space Exploration Room.
It contains a beautiful model of the Moon
and many interesting facts about our galaxy.
Next, the 3D Science Cinema.
We show short movies here every hour about
life under the ocean and in outer space,
and children would really love this place.
To go there, from the information desk, go straight ahead.
The cinema is on your left, opposite the
printing hub, through the staff room.
If you still have time and energy, go
to the Virtual Reality Zone
on the other wall of the cinema.
We provided special headsets for you to wear,
giving you a chance to visit places like
the top of a mountain or the bottom
of the sea without ever leaving the room.
That's an overview of our museum.
You can...
Did you get all of them?
Now let's check the answers together.
Question 11.
The speaker starts by mentioning a space
full of science books and kits.
She says that immediately as you enter the
building through the main entrance, the shop is
on your right.
The only location on the right of the main entrance is A.
So, the answer is A.
Question 12.
Evolution of Computers Gallery.
Next, we look for the room directly across
from the shop.
The speaker states it is on the other
side of the entrance, which means the gallery
is on the left of the main entrance.
Option B is directly opposite room A.
So, the answer is B.
Question 13.
Renewable Energy Exhibit.
From the computer gallery at location B that
we just found, the speaker tells us to
walk a bit further to a room located
halfway up the wall.
We can see on the map that option I
is above room B, situated halfway along
the left-hand side.
So, the answer is option I.
Question 14.
Robotics Lab.
The speaker suggests heading along the right-hand wall.
She notes it is right opposite the information desk
and mentions a cafe is located there,
allowing you to watch the engineers through large windows.
We can see that option C is opposite
the information desk on the right side.
And there is also a small cafe inside room C.
Some might guess that it is option D,
but it is incorrect.
So, the answer is C.
Question 15.
Space Exploration Room.
If you keep walking toward the back of
the building, the speaker points us to the
far top right-hand corner.
We can easily see that option E is
in the very corner room at the top right.
So, the answer is E.
Question 16.
3D Science Cinema.
Next is the cinema.
From the information desk, the speaker says to
go straight ahead.
The cinema is on your left, past the
staff room and opposite the printing hub.
Option G is straight ahead from the center,
on the left side, next to the staff room.
So, the answer is G.
Question 17.
Virtual Reality Zone.
Finally, we find the virtual reality zone.
The speaker describes it as being on the
other wall of the cinema.
Option H shares a wall with room G
in the top left area.
So, the answer is H.
Alright, that's it for today's lesson.
Don't forget to do the exercises and practice
what you've learned regularly.
Goodbye and see you in the next lesson.